A merciless crime turns a man into an outlaw.
Batman: Year One is a action, animation, crime film directed by Sam Liu.
A wealthy playboy named Bruce Wayne and a Chicago cop named Jim Gordon both
return to Gotham City where their lives unexpectedly intersect.
Batman / Bruce Wayne (voice), played by Ben McKenzie.
Jim Gordon (voice), played by Bryan Cranston.
Selina (voice), played by Eliza Dushku.
Commissioner Loeb (voice), played by Jon Polito.
Falcone (voice), played by Alex Rocco.
Detective Essen (voice), played by Katee Sackhoff.
Batman: Year One is a 2011 American adult animated superhero film based on
the four-issue story arc of the same name printed in 1987.
It was directed by Lauren Montgomery and Sam Liu.
The film premiered at Comic-Con on July 22 and was
officially released on October 18, 2011.
It is the 12th film released under the DC Universe Animated Original Movies
banner and was released on DVD, Blu-ray and digital copy.
The film received positive reviews upon release for its
animation and faithfulness to the source material.
It was also a commercial success, bringing in $6.1
million on a budget of $3.5 million.
The film explores themes of superhero, based on comic,
vigilante, police corruption, based on graphic novel.
The tone is emotional and intense.